visionworkseyewear.com 2015-12-18

# Online Privacy Policy | Visionworks

(Updated June 26, 2014)

At Visionworks of America, Inc. (“Visionworks”) is committed to respecting the privacy rights and concerns of all users of this website (the “Site”) (we refer to the Site and the services made available through the Site collectively as the “Site Features”). As such, we have established this Privacy Policy so that you can know our practices regarding the collection and use of information about visitors to the Site. The Site is intended to provide information and a number of different services to assist you in evaluating and shopping for various products sold by Visionworks.

We use information that we collect from you to efficiently provide the Site Features. By visiting the Site or using any of the Site Features, your consent to Visionworks’ collection, use, storage, deletion and disclosure of information relating to you as set forth in this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is only applicable to the Site and not to any other website that you may be able to access from the Site which may have its own data collection and use practices and policies.

  1. ## Information We Collect

Visionworks does not collect personal information unless you voluntarily provide it to us. We do, however, collect certain types of information and ask for personal information in certain circumstances, such as when you set up a User Account, use the Frame Finder™ service, request custom alerts and notifications regarding particular products and product categories, indicate your favorite products, and search for products on the Site. The following sections describe the type of information we collect and how we collect it.

    1. ### Information You Give Us

All users may visit the public areas of the Site without disclosing any personal information about themselves.However, in order to use certain Site Features, you may be asked for, or you may choose to provide, certain personally identifiable information (“PII”), such as your name, email address, mailing address, phone number and similar information. We will not collect PII from you while you use the Site Features unless you voluntarily provide it to us or authorize us to collect such information. When you complete a registration form to create a User Account, we require you to provide us with relevant PII.

    2. ### Cookies.

Like many websites, we employ the use of “cookies” in certain areas of our Site to allow us to provide information that is targeted to your interests and make your online experience more convenient (for instance, by reducing the number of times you have to re-enter your password). Cookies are small bits of electronic information that a website sends to a visitor’s browser and are stored on your hard drive. We may use cookies or similar tools to learn about your preferences and Internet session information, to record information including your likely state of residence, the web pages that you access and for how long, whether you return to the Site, and whether a particular email is opened. We do not receive or record any personal information in the cookies we use and are never tied to anything that could be used to identify you. We may encode our cookies so that only we can interpret the information stored in them. Although most web browsers automatically accept cookies, you may choose to change your browser to block cookies that or to notify you when you are sent a cookie. Most cookies are “session cookies,” meaning that they are automatically deleted at the end of a session and you are always free to decline our cookies if your browser permits. You can still use the Site if your browser is set to reject cookies.

    3. ### Log Information.

Our servers automatically track certain information about you as you use our Site. This information may include the URL that you just came from, which URL you go to next, what browser you are using, and your IP address. Our site logs do generate certain kinds of non-identifying site usage data, such as the number of hits and visits to our Site. This information is used for internal purposes by technical support staff to provide better services to the public and may also be provided to others, but the statistics contain no personal information and cannot be used to gather such information.

    4. ### Favorites and Custom Alerts.

You may choose to submit information pertaining to your areas of interest, including the designation of certain categories of content as “favorites” or the like. Similarly, you may choose to sign-up for customized alerts and notifications pertaining to certain products or product categories featured on the Site. This information is used to personalize the Site Features and tailor the Site to your particular preferences.

    5. ### User Content.

You may choose to submit content to the Site (hereinafter, “User Content”), including personal photographs for use in connection with the Frame Finder™ service. This User Content will be used to facilitate delivery of the Site Features.

    6. ### Usage Activity.

When you use the Site Features we may track your usage history, including search history and the particular content you viewed. This usage history will be used for your convenience, so that you can easily access past searches and content of interest.

  2. ## Sharing of Information

We may use personal information that you provide to us to personalize your profile information, maintain, customize and add new resources and services, and allow communication and interaction between you and Visionworks, and between Visionworks and its operating personnel. In addition, we will share the personal information we collect from you under the following circumstances:

    1. ### Direct Communication.

We may send emails or regular mail to you in connection with your transaction or business relationship with us. If you sign up on our online registration page, we may send email to you concerning special offers, promotions, and eye exam and contact lens replenishment reminders consistent with any email preferences selected by you on the registration page. You may also provide your address information for inclusion on our email or regular mail lists in person at one of our stores. Visionworks or one of Visionworks’ affiliated service providers may contact you by phone, email, or regular mail in connection with the provision of goods or services to you or in response to an inquiry from you. If you do not wish to receive special offers or promotional mailings, you may be removed from our email or regular mail lists through the use of any of the “Control of Your Information & Opt-Out Methods” listed below.

    2. ### Reputable Marketers.

Some of the information we collect may be shared with other reputable marketers to bring you offers of interest, and, if personally identifiable information is collected in connection with a joint promotion, it may be provided to that joint promoter for marketing and research purposes. If you prefer that we do not share your name and address with other reputable marketers, you may contact us using the “Control of Your Information & Opt-Out Methods“ listed below and request that your name be marked as ”do not share.“

    3. ### Protection of Rights.

We will share personal information if we have a good faith belief that (i) access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process, such as a court order or subpoena, or a request by law enforcement or governmental authorities, (ii) such action is appropriate to enforce the Terms of Use for the Site, including any investigation of potential violations thereof, (iii) such action is necessary to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues associated with the Site Features, or (iv) such action is appropriate to protect the rights, property or safety of Visionworks, its employees, users of the Site Features or others. 

    4. ### Asset Transfers.

If we become involved in a merger, acquisition or other transaction involving the sale of some or all of Visionworks’ assets, user information, including personal information collected from you through your use of the Site Features, could be included in the transferred assets. Visitors to the Site will be notified via a prominent notice on the Site for thirty (30) days prior to a change of ownership or control of user information held by us.

    5. ### Service Providers.

We may share your personal information with service providers that we engage for the purpose of processing information on our and your behalf. We require these entities to comply with this Privacy Policy and appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

In addition, we may share with third parties user information in the form of aggregated non-personal information. This non-identifying information may include, for example, the patterns, trends, preferences, and other collective characteristics of our users. Disclosure of this information serves to help us and our marketing partners evaluate and tailor our communications, advertisements, services and general business practices to the needs of users of the Site Features. 

  3. ## Control Of Your Information & Opt-Out Methods

You may request us to correct, update or delete any of the information we have collected from you by sending an email to us at [WebMaster@visionworks.com](mailto:WebMaster@visionworks.com) and we will attempt to fulfill your request. We may choose not to fulfill any request that we determine is unreasonable, unduly burdensome or impractical or that constitutes a threat to the privacy or rights of others. You may also request to be removed from any of our email lists by clicking on an unsubscribe link where provided on our emails and following the related instructions. Should you have any questions or concerns regarding personal information or privacy-related issues, please contact us by sending an email to [WebMaster@visionworks.com](mailto:WebMaster@visionworks.com).

  4. ## Security

The personal information that you provide to us is stored on servers, which are located in secured facilities with restricted access, and protected by protocols and procedures designed to ensure the security of such information. In addition, we restrict access to personal information to Visionworks employees, independent contractors and agents who need to know this information in order to develop, operate and maintain the Site Features. All Visionworks personnel who have access to this information are trained in the maintenance and security of such information. However, no server, computer or communications network or system, or data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect user information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or through the use of any of the Site Features and you acknowledge and agree that you provide such information and engage in such transmissions at your own risk. Once we receive a transmission from you, we will endeavor to maintain its security on our systems. 

  5. ## Minor’s Privacy

The Site is not targeted towards, nor intended for use by, anyone under the age of 18. We do not market our products or services to children (although we do market some of our products and services for children to their parents), and we do not knowingly permit persons under the age of 18 to register or provide personally identifiable information on the Site. The provision of personally identifiable information by children on the Site is strictly prohibited. We encourage parents to supervise and participate in their children’s Internet activities, and we urge children to exercise caution and consult their parents before providing any personally identifiable information on the Internet.

  6. ## Notification of Changes

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time and we will post all changes on this page. Users are encouraged to check this page periodically for any material changes to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not supersede or replace our **HIPAA Privacy Notice** found **here**. Our HIPAA Privacy Notice addresses more specifically our privacy practices and a user’s rights concerning any health information that we may receive or maintain concerning the user.

  7. ## Mediation

You also agree that, in the event any dispute or claim arises out of or relating to your use of the Site or the Site Features or this Privacy Policy that you and Visionworks will attempt in good faith to negotiate a written resolution of the matter directly between the parties. You agree that if the matter remains unresolved for forty-five (45) days after notification (via certified mail or personal delivery) that a dispute exists, all parties shall join in mediation services in Bexar County, Texas with a mutually agreed mediator in an attempt to resolve the dispute. Should you file any arbitration claims, or any administrative or legal actions without first having attempted to resolve the matter by mediation, then you agree that you will not be entitled to recover attorneys’ fees, even if you would otherwise be entitled to them.

  8. ## Questions? Contact Us

If you have any questions about our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at the following address: [WebMaster@visionworks.com.](mailto:WebMaster@visionworks.com)

  9. ## Terms of Service

Please read the Terms of Use governing the use of the Site and the Site Features.

(Updated August 27, 2013)

Click here to download the HIPAA Privacy Notice pdf.

This notice describes how Medical information about you may be used and disclosed and how you can get access to this information.

Click Here to view Protecting Competitively Sensitive Information Policy pdf.

[](http://get.adobe.com/reader/)Note: To view the PDF documents, you will need Acrobat Reader from Adobe. [Download Acrobat Read now](http://get.adobe.com/reader/ "Download Acrobat Read now.").
